Next, I will integrate some of the basic problems that we encounter in the process of using our usual Marvelous Designer in our small snake production process, and then share it with you.
First of all, before we make this snake, we need to make a snake's inner egg first.
So let's draw a snake-shaped board first.
Here we can draw this board into a straight board.
Because later we will use the Morph Target function of OBJ to transform it.
In the process of using Marvelous Designer,
often people will say, why is there a part missing in the board I made?
It's often because the board you made is too small.
In our software, the Morph Target is 20.
You can see that after opening the grid display,
the part missing here is actually because the grid is not enough and cannot be flattened.
So let's reduce the Morph Target a little bit.
For example, here I reduce it to 1.
You can see that the place where there was space before
has now been lined up and filled by smaller grids.
Then you can also go according to the needs.
You need to appropriately increase the Morph Target,
because we all know that when the Morph Target is relatively small,
the grid may be more.
Then we adjust it here.
When adjusting a curve with the Editor-in-Chief tool,
sometimes you will find that it will affect many parts.
It's because the Editor-in-Chief is to identify our straight points.
So if we need to adjust this curve curve in more detail,
we can use the Editor-in-Chief function
to add a curve point and adjust it.
Also, in this transition point,
we can use the
Editor-in-Chief tool to make it more rounded.
Yes.
Then we can adjust it a little bit
and do this other part.
Next, we can increase the Blending Thickness
to increase the thickness of the side of the board.
Here you can see that after I increase the Blending Thickness,
you can't see the thickness of the side.
This is because I am now using a single-sided display,
which is the texture surface.
We need to switch to the dense texture surface
to see the thickness of the board.
This is why some of you
will say in the process of using Marvelous Designer,
why I increased the thickness but there is no display.
It may be because there is no thickness display.
After that,
we can adjust the number of segments on the side
in the edge curve here.
This is in the Marvelous Designer
2024.2 version.
It is one of our main updates.
It is a new update in the 2024 version.
We can set the number of segments on the side.
If the number of segments on the side is 0,
there is no grid on the side.
We only have the front and back panels.
If the number of segments is relatively small,
it is a straight line.
After you increase the number of segments,
the number of segments will be more and more,
and the number of segments will be more and more.
It looks like a rice cooker now, doesn't it?
It's okay.
It will become that snake later.
Now it is a very long rice cooker.
We use the UV fill function in the UV editor
to fill it in.
After that,
we can remove this OBJ.
Now we can give it a straight line.
When you remove it,
you can adjust it according to your needs.
We need to select the thick one here
to remove its thickness.
Then the same UV coordinates,
because we just used the UV fill function
in the UV editor,
we can remove it.
Because I changed the new recording equipment today,
I used the recording equipment that I usually use for recording tutorials.
Now let's open a virtual model.
Here I am using the model of the child in Marvel's Designer.
After arranging this snake on the arrangement point,
it is still in a straight line state,
which is a straight board state.
We can adjust the direction of this board
in the arrangement.
You can see that it will be like a snake
hovering on something.
It will form a spiral shape.
Then we adjust the frame of the board.
The frame that it arranges
will be closer to the center of the arrangement board.
It will be closer to the center of the arrangement board.
Then we can quickly
make it a snake
hovering together.
Then we will
put this shape
or the one we adjusted later
based on this shape,
a snake's center board,
and then we will make it a Morph Target.
and then,
to prevent the board to fall off,
we can use the 3D background right button
in the model properties panel
choose the gravity in the model properties panel
and change its weight to 0.
Then in Marvel's Designer
we will see that
in the previous step,
you can adjust the radius
In the previous step, if our virtual model is only hidden and does not reactivate, it will actually still have a bump.
Because some friends use other 3D software, they will admit that if they hide a board or a model, it will not have a bump with other models or other materials.
But in Marvelous Designer, if you want a model or a material that does not participate in the simulation, remember to reactivate it.
It is useless to hide the light.
By the way, the content I am talking about now may also have something to do with the draw.
So everyone should listen to it seriously.
Then the gravity, I should have changed the gravity later.
Now this one is the same.
I haven't changed it yet.
The ground is like this.
Because there is a conflict on the ground in our software, if we don't turn off the ground conflict, the board will fall on the ground.
So you can find the ground in the simulation property and turn off its conflict.
So it will keep falling down.
So we have some models that if it is below the ground, you may turn off the ground conflict like this.
Then I will show you.
I changed the gravity to 0 here.
When I change the gravity to 0, the board will no longer fall down due to gravity.
But because we just have this model, it still has a conflict.
So in the moment of opening the simulation, this board will have some bump effect.
It's just that it has this force, so it will still move a little.
But it doesn't matter.
We can add a fixed needle to it in each part when we open the simulation.
When modeling, press the W key to click the board.
You can create a fixed needle on the position you click.
So you can fix the grid of the board in the 3D window.
Then adjust the shape of this snake.
And then I finally twisted it into this shape.
And then I'm going to make another OBJ of this model.
The convenience of this operation is that
we will later make one based on the current straight board shape.
It goes outside to make the following boards.
Then finally use Morph Target to transform it.
So our board will automatically be wrapped outside the center board.
Then you can do the transformation of the model.
So the straight board is more convenient to arrange and adjust.
Yes, this is making a snake.
Although it looks like a spoon.
And then just when the model is loading,
it will talk about a hint.
That is, there is no arrangement point.
Unable to automatically generate an arrangement point.
This is because in Marvelous Designer,
I just introduced a default virtual model.
And then our snake is on this child's leg.
It's because Marvelous Designer is identifying the model with hands and feet,
and then there is a head model,
a human-shaped model.
It can be automatically generated and used to arrange the board.
But if your model is not an A pose or a T pose,
or your model does not have a head,
it cannot be identified.
In addition to these situations that I mentioned above,
your model, if its unit is wrong,
there will also be problems.
So we can see some here.
For example,
for example,
I am now changing the posture of this model.
After I change my posture,
it will not be able to identify the position of its arms and feet.
Just like T pose and A pose,
it is easier to identify.
For example,
if I make this model fall into love,
I will choose the automatic body arrangement point here.
It will talk about the hint,
that is,
it is not possible to arrange the arrangement point on the model.
For models like this,
we will usually use T pose or A pose to make clothes first.
After that,
we will use this model with movement
to make morph target in the form of OBJ,
which is transformation.
This will be easier.
In addition,
even if our T pose and A pose are normal,
but my unit is wrong,
for example,
its original unit is mm,
I choose mm here,
then you can see that this model is compared to the ground,
you can see that it is very, very large.
In this way,
there is no way to automatically generate the arrangement point.
So sometimes,
even if your model is human-shaped,
and it looks normal,
but it still jumps this hint,
it is probably because your unit was chosen wrong.
It's not just that the unit is chosen big,
it will also have problems if it is chosen small.
For example,
I choose 10% of the ratio that I give it in here,
then it compares this ground,
you can see that it may not have a large grid,
it may not have a large grid.
In this case,
it also has no way to automatically generate the arrangement point.
And it's not just that there is no way to automatically generate the arrangement point,
after we choose the wrong unit,
for example,
I create a version,
because Marvelous Designer created the default particle diameter of the version is 20,
in this case,
it has a very large grid,
compared to this virtual model.
Even if we reduce this particle diameter to 10,
that is,
the distance between the peak of a grid and a peak of a grid is 10 mm,
10 mm is 1 cm,
compared to this virtual model,
your grid is still very large,
then the version will not have a very fine fold when it is simulated.
And it's not just this,
like our virtual model,
its default surface diameter is 3 mm,
that is,
it will have 3 mm thick air around it.
If your model is originally normal height,
it may be 1.8 meters,
3 mm is very small compared to the virtual model,
but if your unit is wrong,
then the air thickness of 3 mm will be very large.
You can see that we have a model with a normal proportion.
The version that was made before can cover the whole body,
now it may only have one corner so big,
so pay attention to the unit when inserting.
Then here we are based on this version just now,
and then give it a version extension,
just make it wider,
cover the thickness of the side just now,
because after we squeeze the thickness out to the side,
its version will be larger.
Then use the original version,
which is definitely not enough.
Okay,
then we can start to prepare
the outer fabric of this snake.
Because we usually make this kind of fur toy,
or some dolls with inflating effect,
we will use the cologne layer.
And then I really use the cologne layer
to quickly make a front and back panel for it,
because the cologne layer,
it not only can quickly copy the shape of the panel,
and then it will automatically create the corresponding line
on the outside of the panel and on the inside of the line,
it will be more convenient,
it will also be automatically arranged in the 3D window.
Okay, then,
at this time,
there will be a problem,
in our common model,
it will have some strange shapes,
many times because the panel is too tight,
because in the case of you having a sewing line,
like this closed position,
for example,
you can see this panel,
it is wrapped from head to foot,
then in this case,
you may not be able to see,
it has some deformation,
very serious position,
but once you add the sticker,
or it is at the bottom,
like this panel,
it is,
after we finish it,
it is longer than the internal panel,
then in this case,
it will not be thin at the bottom,
or it will not be wrapped inside,
this hard surface part,
it will be squeezed out,
a very strange shape,
or that is,
you usually do the earliest,
the earliest basic model,
or the most basic layer of clothing,
before,
that is, before completion,
remember to open the Alt key first,
open the display hard drive,
see if its hard drive has a red part,
the red part,
is the position where the stretch deformation is more serious,
like this,
the stretch deformation is a serious position,
it is very likely to affect,
the subsequent other external panels you made on this basis,
because the layer inside you,
it may be attached,
or it can,
it may be attached to your model's body,
but it is impossible to be wrapped everywhere,
for example,
like this snake,
its bottom here,
because it can't,
there is nothing wrapped,
it will be squeezed out,
it will squeeze out such a strange shape,
so everyone,
when making clothes,
remember to take a look,
whether your model has this,
is your fabric,
whether there is a stretch deformation,
a serious part,
or a leg,
then you can do it,
and it is,
it's just,
the side of the person,
it has thickness,
so you can not just follow this,
the flat panel,
because you just follow the flat panel,
it is just a slice,
the side of the person,
or the side of the object,
has thickness,
your cloth,
it must be more than,
it has as much stretch deformation as it,
is at least there may be half,
this thickness,
so do not,
So don't just look at the outline of the face.
This is definitely not enough.
Then just adjust the side a little bit.
When I adjust the face, I still change it part by part.
Not a whole piece.
Because I tried a whole piece before.
I accidentally did it too much.
Then go back here.
This is a demonstration for everyone.
You can see our version.
After opening the simulation, one is the clothes on the right side.
The clothes on the right side are very obvious.
You can feel it tight.
One is that you will see it like this.
It should be a straight line.
The position of the joint has some twists.
There is also a fabric.
For example, our top T-shirt.
The bottom will keep going up.
The clothes should be heavy.
It should fall down.
But now it's too tight.
It will keep going up.
It's like being under pressure.
It will squeeze the thinnest part of the human body.
So whether you are making pants or clothes.
For example, when you make pants.
It may squeeze to the knee position.
Because the knee position is usually the thinnest.
Then people.
The clothes.
It will move to the waist.
It will move up or down automatically.
Because it's too tight.
And the left side.
So this bag will fall down by itself.
But sometimes.
We do it because we make clothes.
It will need this.
The board stays in this position.
So sometimes.
The easiest way.
You must increase the friction.
Once the friction rate is increased to a very high value.
Because of this board.
Its friction force has become greater.
So it won't move very fast.
But in fact.
It will be a little bit.
The position is biased.
But in general.
It will stay in this position.
This method.
It can be used in some simple.
The structure of the board.
But if this.
The board.
It has to participate in animation production.
Or you are outside.
You need to have some.
Natural cloth effect.
You may use this friction force.
The method.
It won't be so good.
And then.
In addition.
Is this board.
You can put it.
Slightly enlarge the size.
Don't let it be like this.
So tight.
There is one.
It can be used.
Fake sewing function.
To put.
The two ends of this board.
Fixed.
On the internal clothing.
above.
This way.
It won't slide down.
Then we go back to.
The part of the snake.
Sometimes.
After I'm done.
I'll press Alt 4.
Open.
Display transparent picture.
After opening.
I will.
According to the current.
These fish.
To slightly.
Adjust the board.
And then.
When doing this.
Tighter.
Board.
I will.
There is no.
Inside.
The surface.
The structure.
All are a little lower.
Otherwise.
Model.
It will have a layer.
Of air.
Wall.
The air wall.
Will not let the piece of.
Passing.
Then it may look.
It is not so sweet.
And then.
Just continue.
Adjust.
This.
She's.
A sheet.
He.
Of.
The.
We.
Now we do is.
Basis.
She's one.
to the top of this model.
The effect of the fur and bowl
will be completed by carving another layer on this layer.
Okay, when we usually adjust this panel,
if it is due to some adjustment operations,
or the expansion of the panel line,
or the operation of the border of the panel line,
which leads to excess curve points,
we can use the optimization curve point function
to optimize the curve point.
After we have adjusted it,
we will carve another layer on the outer side of the column,
and we can carve it out.
Then we use the inner side of the column
because the column will identify the opposite side of the panel.
This panel is facing the back,
so we use the inner side of the column
to carve it out.
Then we use the inner side of the column to carve it out.
Okay, now there is a common question
that everyone asks,
which is in Marvelous Designer,
why is there a gap between my panels and the panels?
This is because one is when you are using the column layer function,
or when you sew a panel to the inner line,
the fur and bowl line it automatically generates is Turned,
this type of fur and bowl line.
The type of this fur and bowl line,
it will affect your,
the panel in the panel line is the position of this created fur and bowl line,
its gap between the two panels,
because it is actually called a fold in Turn,
it is to put the two panels as two layers,
so it will apply our fabric thickness again.
At this time, if we change its type of fur and bowl line to a pin,
it will go back to the two sides of the pasted together.
the two sides of the pasted together.
For example, I will now show you a demonstration,
for example, I will now show you a demonstration,
we are also directly to the same layer,
then it is the use of the fold.
Then if we change it to the pin,
Then it will automatically change,
then you will see the thickness of our side,
no matter how you modify it,
for example, the contrast thickness,
its side, even if you use Turn,
the distance between the plates and the plates will not be affected by the conflict thickness.
The conflict thickness is the air and collision thickness around the other places.
If you want to affect the thickness between the plates and the plates on the side,
you have to go to our fabric and adjust its fabric thickness.
For example, if the fabric thickness is set to 3 and its fabric thickness is increased,
you will see that the gap between the sewing line and the sewing line will be larger.
No matter how you change the conflict thickness, it will not affect the gap on the side.
This is because of the distance between the plates and the plates.
If we turn on the thickness display, you will see that the seam allowance will set the two plates along the sewing line as two layers.
So it will definitely make the thickness of this fabric,
the thickness of this fabric,
reflected in this position.
So how much is the thickness of your fabric?
Its side of this conflict is the distance seen from the naked eye.
If we, because why does it show that there is a gap?
It's because it's all one-sided display.
It's not showing the thickness.
If you go back to the thickness display,
you will see that it is because you have to set it to two layers.
If the thickness on the side is not reflected,
there is no gap.
These two-layer plates,
they will overlap.
It's not two-layer.
This is why sometimes we have the most common problem.
Basically,
two days later,
there may be a message asking why there is a gap between our plates.
One is because you didn't turn on the thickness display,
so it looks very strange.
Another one is that the type of sewing line you set is the overlap.
It will have such an effect.
Because of the overlap,
its basic logic is to put two plates or two layers along the seam line.
Another one is that when you are leading out this OBJ,
you can also set it for it.
For example, you don't actually need its thickness.
You don't want its side thickness.
You can only choose whether to merge the top points
or you can only choose whether to open the joint close to the top point.
One is when you go to the joint top point,
if you choose,
this is not the same as the previous version.
In the previous version,
whether your sewing line type is TURN or Custom Angle,
when you sew,
as long as you choose to merge the top points,
it will merge the top points on the left and right sides of the sewing line together.
But in the new version,
it's different.
In the new version,
you only choose to sew when you sew,
and then choose to merge the top points.
It will merge the top points on the two sides of the sewing line together.
But if sometimes,
under special circumstances,
you need to merge the top points and the top points
in other ways,
you may need to use
the function to merge the top points in the same way.
Here we choose to merge the top points in the same way.
Then click on the top point to merge,
you will see that the top points on its side will merge together.
This function is also for
the convenience of everyone.
When the model is not thick,
you can merge it,
for example,
the top and bottom lines together.
Then this is the distance of merging.
For example,
I set the merge distance here to be relatively small.
The merge distance is 3.
Only the distance between the points is less than 3 to be merged.
When the space on your side is relatively thick,
it is not merged.
Here you can adjust it according to your needs.
For example,
I set it to 10.
The space on its side is 10.
The thickness of the plate on its side
is definitely not as thick as 10.
The distance between the points is not more than 10.
At this time,
we choose to merge the top points in the same way.
Then it will merge the top points on the side together.
If I choose here is not a peak,
but a peak,
you will see that
its current simulation effect
is completely different from the previous one.
You can clearly see that this is a two-layer plate.
Right?
It looks very clear on the side.
But if you change it to a peak,
it will be different.
When you cut back the single-sided display,
that is, when you display it with no thickness,
you will see that it is originally merged together.
Here we will do another demonstration.
This is a two-layer plate with the sides merged together.
Then we change its spring line type from the default peak to the top peak.
Then simulate it again.
Because the spring line between the two plates
can be very clear,
like being pressed by a moving apple,
this spring line is identified as two layers.
So the first one you will see
when we change it to a peak,
that is, the moment of turn,
there is a gap between the two plates
along the position of the spring line.
There is another one.
It is in the position of the spring line.
It will be very sharp like being pressed by a moving apple.
This is when the spring line type is set to turn.
So you can modify the spring line type
according to your own needs
when you usually use software.
Then here is another proposal.
Because the plate is sewn to the inner line,
its spring line type cannot be changed.
Even if you choose a peak,
it will automatically become a peak.
This is because the line on the inner line itself,
when another plate is sewn together with it,
it will be identified as two layers.
It should also be a two-layer plate.
So when we set default,
the inner line here
cannot be modified by the spring line type.
It can only be sewn with this attribute.
Because no matter what plate is attached to another plate,
for example, the pocket is attached to the outside of the clothes,
it must have its own independent thickness,
it will not be stuck in.
But if you want to stick it in,
you can adjust it in other software.
So here we are in the process of
changing the spring line type
from the original peak to the peak.
In addition,
we will also change the back to the outside of this plate
and choose to turn the surface,
so that the front position of its hair line
turns outward.
This way,
it can keep the direction of its fabric in the same direction.
It's tender.
OK,
now let's move on to the next step.
We will now use a different fabric for the front.
It's a fabric called the front half.
Now,
when we turn the front half,
it is printed.
When we turn the front half,
it's in the center.
We then replace the front half with the back half.
According to this,
the front half has the appearance of a straight line,
but when we turn the front half with the front half,
it will not be immediately painted.
And we will apply a different fabric to the outside layer.
Because the inside layer is mainly used to wrap the fabric of this snake,
snake,
We usually do, whether it's doing this kind of small object or doing clothes, maybe we'll do two layers.
In fact, you can imagine it as the layer inside is used to fix its position
to ensure that these outer folds can be deepened in the area I set.
Then the outer layer, we will make different adjustments and modifications to it
to make it in the position of the wrinkle line, because in fact, the most effective way to limit its position is the position of the wrinkle line.
Then we can make other adjustments to other parts.
For example, now I apply a different fabric to the outer layer.
The main reason is that I want it to be more obvious.
In this way, I will apply a fabric to the outer layer separately,
and then apply this fabric separately.
First of all, we have to ensure pressure balance.
So, because we just used the flip surface,
we found the surface flip function to ensure that it has two left and right panels.
They can be turned over.
The direction of the hair line is relative.
When we set the pressure, we must pay attention to the pressure to be balanced.
Otherwise, the flat surface will be blown away.
So now, we set the pressure to face the outside on both sides.
For example, this side is to the left, and the right side is to the right.
So its pressure is balanced.
Then, we will go to the physical properties.
Reduce its tail sand strength and gold sand strength.
And, if its tensioning performance becomes better,
the same pressure can cause different effects.
It is because of its tensioning performance.
so we blow a balloon,
certainly more convenient than blowing a rubber,
or a jeans or a flipper.
The balloon will not inflate too much,
but the balloon has its own elasticity.
The bigger it is, the more it will expand under external forces, so we will apply a different fabric to the outer layer separately, and then apply the outer layer of the fine fine sand strength.
Because the fine fine sand strength of the toe line strength, they all affect the stretch performance of a board in different directions.
The lower this value, the easier it is to stretch, so under the same pressure setting, the effect of its expansion will be more obvious.
Next, we can prepare to insert the model as a Morph Target.
The higher the deformation factor, the slower its deformation speed will be, and the more stable it will be.
If I directly do not use any fixed function to use Morph Target, you will see that it is because the deformation speed is very fast, so some panels are protruding out.
So here we can see that the deformation speed is very fast, so some panels are protruding out.
Then we can first use a fixed pin to fix it on the side of the inner layer of the board.
Because this board itself is not completely attached to the inner layer of the board, so we do not attach a fixed pin to the entire board.
We just need to double-click on the outer layer of the board, and you can create a fixed pin along this outer layer of the board.
So we create a fixed pin along a circle,
and we use a fixed pin to fix it on the inner layer of the board.
So that it is in this position, which is the position of the sewing line.
These grid points will follow our model.
So after I use Morph Target, these positions will follow the deformation because they are already fixed on the model.
So after I use Morph Target, these positions will follow the deformation.
Then we will have some panel penetration problems here.
We will explain to you in a while.
How to adjust when you encounter such a material reversal and its hair line is turned over on the back.
First of all, because we have many layers of this board now, but the main problem is the inner layer.
So in the outer layer, we use the panel part made of the cloned layer.
We will give it a reverse fire first, and then we can directly add the outer layer to the outer layer.
So we can add the outer layer, and add the inner layer.
These functions will attach the outer layer to the inner layer.
So now we have made the reverse fire on the outer two layers.
First of all, we encounter such a penetration problem.
For example, you can see that the fabric is actually worn out.
We will use the selection grid tool to find its position.
My personal operating habit is to use the selection grid first,
For example, I will find it in the 3D window, one is that I will click on this position and then find it in the 2D window according to this blue auxiliary point.
Because of the selection grid tool, it can't choose to hide or say the position that you can't see in your current view.
In other words, it can't choose the back, it has to be selected according to the position that you can select in your current window.
So I usually do a point positioning in the 3D window and then go to the 2D window to find this grid.
Can the outer model be imported into the fabric?
Can be imported, pay attention to your UV.
The main thing is that the UV does not overlap, do not cross the line, and do not try Chinese, try to use English, and do not have an empty UV line.
Then add, that is, we have a grid here.
After finding it, go to the 2D window and select it.
Use the selection grid tool to adjust the part that is wrong like this.
Then take a look again.
Next is here.
Here we are dealing with the problem of this grid reversal.
One is that when your version is not stable, press Alt2 to switch to the texture surface, which does not show the thickness.
That is, under the texture surface display type, it will show black on the back side of the version.
So you will see that this position is black on both sides, which proves that this version has been flipped on both sides.
So we are going to adjust it now.
Then choose the grid tool to find it.
The correct position should be here, but you can see that it has been flipped to the other side.
So we choose it and turn it to the correct position.
Then here is also to select it, select it in the 2D window, and then turn it to the correct position.
Connection position.
Okay, now it's basically done.
Then, like this position now, it is the same.
Find it where it should be.
Then select it, you can choose a little more, it doesn't matter.
After selecting it, just pull it out with the positioning ball.
Then we can show the part of the reverse fire just now.
Then here we don't have to choose the grid anymore.
Just add it directly to the outside or add it to the inside.
Adding to the outside is to add the version directly to the outside of the version you just created.
Then we now this small snake model, it is all facing the outside.
So you want to create, you want to add another layer on this layer.
You must add it directly to the outside, not add it to the inside.
Otherwise, this material will be created in the inside of the snake we have adjusted.
Then it was originally outside.
So we choose to add it to the outside.
Then this version is also added to the outside.
Then the add to the outside function, it will automatically arrange the version.
So as long as your inner layer is stable, you add it to the outside function, it will also automatically stabilize it outside.
Yes, this is the latest version of Marvelous Designer.
Then now let's download a material to take a look.
Usually everyone will say that I put two versions, that is, the two sets of clothes I created before.
How can it not be stable when it is put together?
One is the relationship of using layers.
In fact, when we are in a normal stable situation, it is OK to use layers.
It doesn't matter, it can quickly help us to build the version.
But sometimes there is a problem between the version and the version itself.
Or you have a lot of wrinkles on the inner layer of the version.
For example, like my skirt, it will have a lot of wrinkles on the inner part.
When I use the layer function again, it is very likely that there will be wear and tear and instability.
It has already been unstable.
Plus the wrinkle position.
Its.
The surface of contact between the version and the version.
It is possible that the front, the back, the back, the front.
Or the front and the front, the back and the back.
Or the front to the back.
That is, the type and position of the surface it is in contact with is not the same.
When you use layers, it is easy to recognize errors.
Causing you to be unstable, the place is even more unstable.
In this case, we recommend everyone.
There is a hole.
I think everyone can remember.
When your clothes are unstable.
If you set the level.
You cancel the level.
All the levels of the version return to zero.
If you do not set the level.
You can try to set the level.
That is, if there is a level, you cancel the level.
If there is no level when it is not stable.
You give them a try with the level.
You can see here.
After I canceled his level.
He managed it on his own.
It is because of itself.
When it is unstable.
You go to simulate the version.
He may be able to simulate it well.
But after you add the level.
He will add a new layer to identify the part to be identified.
He may be unstable on the one hand.
It will be even more unstable if you apply the level on the other hand.
Then we can put his level here first.
I just canceled it.
Then use the selection grid tool to deal with these differences.
In addition.
There is also a soft selection drag function.
This function.
We can first show the full weight.
And after opening the version that is only used for selection.
Because it is a soft selection.
He will only choose the position of the fabric itself.
When you drag it.
He can go over this gap.
We drag out this layer outside.
This is also a soft selection drag function.
Some of the times it will be used.
He can choose what we can't see.
Or the part of the insertion.
As long as you choose.
The only function is to select the version.
This function.
Then let's take a look.
If I add this clothes.
Can you just avoid this problem?
It's okay.
Because just now.
We just directly.
How to deal with this conflict when there is a conflict between the versions?
Then I usually do the software habit.
It's the habit of using our software to make clothes.
I might put that layer first.
After making it tight.
Then put the outer layer on it.
This will be more stable.
For example, I am now.
First, the outer layer of the inner layer.
Give it a reverse activation.
I put the inner layer of this layer on first.
Because we are going to be in this dress.
Go out and put on that T-shirt.
So I'm going to put on the inner layer of this dress first.
After wearing it.
Then put on the outer layer of the T-shirt.
First of all, I put it on first.
After wearing it.
I will reduce its tail shrinkage.
In our software.
You use the edit text tool.
Click the edit text tool.
Select the version.
You can see its thinking direction.
The direction of the index finger is this arrow.
The direction of the arrow is the golden direction.
Then the one that is 90 degrees with it is the tail.
Under normal circumstances.
You just default.
The horizontal direction is the tail.
If you want your clothes to be tighter.
You can reduce the tail shrinkage.
This is just under normal circumstances.
Okay.
Then we can freeze the inner layer.
The already frozen version.
It is not affected by any external forces.
Formal change.
It will be frozen directly in the 3D window.
But it still has conflicts.
So at this time.
Because it itself has a collision.
We open the external version to simulate.
It will be on the outside of this version.
It will not continue to have an intersection with it.
At this time.
We will apply layers to it.
It will soon be able to simulate.
Outside of the inside of this version.
Just because of the inside.
This layer.
We just used shrinkage.
Make it become very tight.
Very tight fabric.
Then it will stick tightly to the model's body.
So we will have more.
Let the outer layer be simulated.
Now we have used the layer.
After that.
It will return the layer to zero.
No matter when.
When you are using Marvelous Designer.
Once your version is simulated.
Remember to return your layer to zero.
Wait a minute.
I will show you.
If you don't return the layer to zero.
How will it be?
In fact.
Sometimes.
When static.
This layer stays there.
It doesn't matter.
Instead.
When doing some dynamic.
Or you want to adjust the posture.
Then its level will be problematic.
I have already simulated it.
After that.
I will give it the inner layer shrinkage.
From the one just set.
For example.
80 or 70.
Return to 100.
Okay.
Now we can take a look.
The outer layer.
Is.
There is this.
Press.
Is.
The level we just set.
Then.
If I go to adjust the posture now.
Just in a very fast.
In the case of movement.
There is a gap.
Between the panels.
Then.
There is a gap.
Because.
My outer panels.
It has layers.
Its level.
It itself will go.
Identify.
Or.
You are already.
Some.
Pressure.
And collision.
When.
It needs to apply quickly.
This collision.
Quick collision processing.
And then.
To deal with this layer.
It will let the panels.
There is a gap between the panels.
In this case.
We put it.
Outer.
Pressure.
Not pressure.
Sorry.
That layer.
Set to zero.
There is a gap.
So.
This is why.
I keep reminding you.
When you are using Marvelous Designer.
Once.
Your panel is stable.
Do not.
Keep the layer.
The layer.
Return to zero.
Layer.
It's just a temporary.
Use of things.
Rather than.
It should be.
A long-term preservation.
Value.
Yes.
So.
Your layer.
After using it once.
Do not use it again.
Or.
He is.
He only.
At a certain time.
It is.
A short time.
Stable.
Then.
Return to zero.
You can.
Then.
Adjust.
A little.
This.
Our.
Stretching performance.
To.
Let it.
The outer layer.
It is more powerful.
Then.
Do animation.
If.
Because.
I see.
There is a question in the chat.
Is.
Come back.
This problem.
Usually.
Do animation.
If.
Well.
We have an animation entry.
You can take a look.
That is.
If you want to do animation.
Or.
Some.
Special posture.
That.
You can take a look.
Because.
Sometimes.
You do animation.
He.
If the speed of movement is too fast.
It is relatively easy.
This problem.
It is also possible.
Or.
Say.
Some.
Parts.
Because.
Now.
We have.
Key.
Real animation.
You.
Even.
Real function.
To.
Repair.
Some.
Parts.
Then.
Here.
I.
Is.
To.
Give.
This.
Little.
Snake.
Two.
Eyes.
We.
In addition.
To.
The system.
These.
Knose.
In addition.
We.
Can.
Define.
The.
Pattern.
But.
We.
Have.
To.
Change.
A.
Whole.
Type.
Instead.
Of.
Changing.
A.
Single.
Knot.
So.
We.
In.
The.
Knot.
If.
We.
To.
Change.
Its.
Size.
We.
Have.
To.
Change.
The.
Pattern.
To.
Make.
In.
The.
Pattern.
We.
Have.
To.
Change.
In.
The.
Pattern.
We.
Have.
Change.
The.
Top.
In.
The.
Pattern.
validation.
Of.
The.
Pattern.
Of.
The.
It is the part that bends up to the ground, so sometimes you customize the button, it will give you a hint that you can't do this.
We can't customize the button because your model may be below the ground, so it can't be registered.
Or its size is very different from the size of Marvelous Designer.
For example, your unit is originally rice, and Marvelous Designer's unit is good rice.
But it can't be customized, or its grid will be very strange.
So in order to prevent this from happening, you can first import your OBJ model into Marvelous Designer,
apply our coordinate system, and export the OBJ to 2G.
And then download it.
The one I just made is called Star, and you can make a shortcut for it.
I just made a star-shaped eye for it.
But I didn't use this eye at the end.
So this is almost the part where we make this little snake.
And if you have any questions during the process of using Marvelous Designer,
you can also add us to the group to ask questions.
I think I will ask questions after I finish the drawing part.